CONTACT DETAILS

akhilaaatif16@gmail.com



Navi Mumbai, Maharashtra



+91 7506784041

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE SIES(Nerul) College of Arts, Science and Commerce (April 2013)

SKILLS

- Java
- Selenium (WebDriver)
- SQL
- Jira Tool
- Apache JMeter
- Cucumber BDD
- Maven
- **TestNG**
- **Appium**

STRENGTHS

- Document preparation
- Test Case preparation
- Knowledge of testing procedures

PERSONAL DETAILS

- Date of Birth: 16th July 1991
- Marital Status: Married
- LinkedIn URL:www.linkedin.com/in/akhila-aatifsabeel-1985b4103
- Languages: English, Hindi, Marathi, Kannada

Akhila Aatif Sabeel

SUMMARY

Having total 7 years of experience in Web application and Mobile application testing as **Automation and Manual tester**. Excellent knowledge and working experience with test planning, test case and test script creation, test execution and test defect reporting. Hands-on experience in automation testing using Selenium WebDriver, BDD Cucumber, Maven, TestNG, Git and GitHub. Collaborating with software developers and quality assurance teams to identify automation testing needs and incorporating them into the development process.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Datacomp Web Technologies India Pvt Ltd

SOFTWARE TESTER

Mumbai

Duration: - 10/2020- 12/2023

- Involved in writing and reviewing the documents i.e.: FS and DS.
- Automation Testing using Breez automation Tool.
- Identifying the test cases for Automation.
- Configured Selenium WebDriver, TestNG, Maven tool and created selenium automation scripts in java using TestNG prior to agile
- Responsible for getting clarification from the Development Team regarding defects
- Responsible for sending progress reports on the weekly basis
- Performing Smoke testing, Functional testing and Regression
- Created detailed test documentation, including test plans, test cases, and test scripts increasing test coverage and improving overall testing accuracy.

NSEIT LIMITED

Client – SBI Life

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Mumbai

Duration: - 12/2018 - 12/2019

Test planning including MTP, Test Cases, Test Scenarios, **Execution Plan and Data Matrix**

- Created functional automation scripts for various module using tools Selenium WebDriver and TestNG.
- Client interaction through status call to discuss the new requirements and issues reported during testing. Communicating with other team's members (Development and Business team) to discuss the requirements and to resolve the Issues
- Defect, Change Control, Ambiguity Tracking and Reporting using HP ALM
- Performing Smoke testing, Functional testing and Regression Testing.

Collabera

Client – IBM INDIA Pvt.Ltd

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Mumbai

Duration: - 07/2018 - 12/2018

- Participated in Testing documentation reviews and walkthroughs, including those for Test plans, Test cases, Test strategies, Test Summary Reports.
- Used Selenium to expand test scenarios to catch more bugs and improve quality.
- Responsible for gathering test execution data on daily basis and sending mail to Team.
- Participated in Sprint Planning, Daily Stand-up, Sprint Review, and Retrospective meeting.

Nucsoft Limited

Software Quality Analyst

Mumbai

Duration: - 12/2014 - 09/2017

- Involved in Review the documents i.e.: FS and DS
- Understanding the client Requirements and projects Functionalities.
 Prepare and Execution of test cases as per requirement.
- Performing Internal Audits.
- Involved in Functional testing. Involved in System testing.
- Preparing Defect Report
- Mapping requirement with test cases.
- Retesting the cases where defect has been raised.